(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T21:45:11.460186",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
しゅわっ！
Fizz!
このライブに来てくれてありがとスバル！
Thank you for coming to this live, Subaru!
今日はみんな楽しんでってねー！
Everyone, enjoy yourselves today!
ちょこっとヤンチャで にこっと元気な
A little mischievous, and cheerfully smiling,
ひらっとスマイル
With a fluttering smile!
会いに行くよ 毎日もっと
I'll go meet you every day, wanting to
楽しくしたい とびきり with アドベンチャー
have more fun with an extraordinary adventure.
よくよく見渡す カートもちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
Even the carts we look out for, I can ride them right.
ひだり ひだり スカートもちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
Left, left, I can wear a skirt properly too!
だからもっと 好きになってもいいよ 一緒に
So it's okay to love me more, together!
大空に飛び立とう 光れ SUNLIGHT
Let's fly up into the great sky, shine, SUNLIGHT!
どんな輝きの中も 強いきらめき
A strong sparkle amidst any brilliance,
君に届いているかな 一ミリでも
I wonder if it reaches you, even by a millimeter.
伝われ VIBES 充電 チャレンジ 全力アクセル
Convey, VIBES! Recharge, challenge, full throttle!
頑張る君へ 一番のりのスマイルを
Sending the very first smile to you who are doing your best.
一番乗りのスマイルを おくるスバルチャンネル
Sending the first-place smile on Subaru Channel,
EVERYDAY 悩み合えい みんなで
EVERYDAY, sharing worries together—
眠れない気持ちに ずばっと駆けつけ お助けしちゃうきっと
Rushing right in to sleepless feelings to help you out for sure,
弱いハートじゃいられないから 強気でいきましょう
We can't have weak hearts, so let's go strong!
はらひらなみすぎて 時々ときめきたい
Fluttering past like waves, sometimes wanting my heart to flutter,
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス東関東
Come anytime, it's Paradise East Kanto all year round!
つもり空 吹き飛ばそう 上がれ SUNLIGHT
Let's blow away the gloomy sky, rise, SUNLIGHT!
どんな暗闇の中も まぶしく照らす
Lighting up brightly even in the pitch-black darkness.
君に見つけてもらえた それだけでも運命なんだ
Just being found by you—that alone is destiny!
もっとずっと道は続いてく 夢に向かって
The road continues on and on, towards our dreams.
一緒に来てくれるかな その手をとって走れ
Will you come along with me? Take my hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで 一番乗りのスマイルを
I'll lead everyone, sending the first-place smile,
おくるスバルチャンネル EVERYDAY 悩みなんてみんなで
On Subaru Channel, EVERYDAY, sharing worries together.
伝えたい 恥ずかしいけれど
I want to convey it, even though it's embarrassing,
伝えたい想い 今なら言える
The feelings I want to share—now I can say them.
君のエルが 力になるよ いつも元気分けてくれて
Your "L" gives me strength, always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can keep doing my best, I can spend days smiling, truly.
ありがとうの気持ちを 歌えたら いいな どんな輝きの中も 強いきらめき
If I could sing my feelings of gratitude, that would be wonderful. A strong sparkle amidst any brilliance,
君に届いているかな 一ミリでも
I wonder if it reaches you, even by a millimeter.
伝われ VIBES 充電 チャレンジ 全力アクセル
Convey, VIBES! Recharge, challenge, full throttle!
頑張る君へ 一番のりのスマイルを
Sending the very first smile to you who are doing your best.
おくるスバルチャンネル EVERYDAY 悩みなんてみんなで
Sending it on Subaru Channel, EVERYDAY, sharing worries together—
眠れない気持ちに ずばっと駆けつけ お助けしちゃうきっと
Rushing right in to sleepless feelings to help you out for sure,
弱いハートじゃいられないから 強気でいきましょう
We can't have weak hearts, so let's go strong!
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス東関東
Come anytime, it's Paradise East Kanto all year round!
つもり空 吹き飛ばそう 上がれ SUNLIGHT
Let's blow away the gloomy sky, rise, SUNLIGHT!
大空スバル 7周年 LIVE 始まる 始まる！
Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary LIVE, it's starting, starting!
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always cause you trouble,
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
And always give you a hard time,
それでも隣にいてくれる 君のそばにずっと
Yet you stay by my side, always right beside you—
曖昧な言葉じゃ 真面目な君には 伝わらない 感情のそのハートを
Vague words won't reach serious you; I want to look into, melt,
覗いてみたい 溶かしてみたい そんなときこんな魔法はどかな
And see your heart of emotions! How about magic like this at times?
やっちゃんのサイン! サイン! サイン! 早くやろっで いいのいいの！
Yay, sign, sign, sign! Hurry up and do it, it's fine, it's fine!
見失うピン ウォッチミーズマッチ
Losing sight of the pin, watch me's match!
あららそうとう以上の展開求められないのよ ごめんね 溢れる想いで空回り
Oh my, developments beyond all expectations can't be demanded, sorry, spinning my wheels with overflowing feelings!
振りかけるhappyなイメージ で振り回すfancyなマジック
Sprinkling a happy image, swinging around a fancy magic,
また君に孤独と言われちゃうけど ほらこんな Day by dayがいい
Being told I'm lonely again by you, but hey, days like this Day by day are great!
こんなDay by dayがいい
Such days are nice, day by day,
あの日から Falling in love with you
ever since that day, falling in love with you.
変わらないから ずっと Only you
It won't change, always only you.
だから ほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
掴めハッピーエンディング
Grab a happy ending!
いつまでも 隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep smiling by your side forever.
ひとりぼっちの毎日そんな
My lonely days, such...
私の前に現れた君は
You, who appeared before me,
同じ寂しさを抱えている とても とても 優しい人
carry the same loneliness—a very, very kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
Even now, there are many worries, but...
もう私も君も一人じゃない
Neither you nor I are alone anymore.
騒がしく愛しいこの日々がずっと続きますように
May these bustling, lovely days continue forever!
飛ばせハッピーなイメージ
Launch a happy image!
とびきりのFancyなマジック
An extraordinary, fancy magic.
また君にしつこく言われそうだけれど
You'll probably nag me about it again, but...
そんなDay by dayがいい
such days are nice, day by day,
あの日から Falling in love with you
ever since that day, falling in love with you.
気付いて欲しいの Loving you
I want you to notice, loving you.
だから ほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
次はいどんなプランニング
What's the next planning?
そしてまた 今日もハプニング
And today brings another happening too.
明日はどんなおかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what funny thing will happen tomorrow.
ずっと隣で見ててね
Keep watching by my side forever!
一期一会で君とだけ！
Only with you in a once-in-a-lifetime encounter!
もう少し眠りたいけど もったいないよ
I want to sleep a little more, but what a waste!
今日はSunday 楽しいこと やりたいこと
Today is Sunday, fun things to do, things I want to do.
ウェイクアップ はじめようよ
Wake up, let's get started!
めくりめく季節君と次のステージへ
Spinning seasons, with you to the next stage!
声を合わせ 扉開けて 駆け出せ迷わずに 転んでも かっこ悪くてもいいじゃない
Open the door, run out without hesitation—even if you fall, it's fine!
Stand up イメージもっと重ねて行くその先で
Stand up, piling up more images beyond that!
一期一会で君とだけ ハイタッチして叩いて 奏でるメロディーを
Only with you, high-five and clap, playing the melody!
合図に走り出せ Go! 君となら怖くない
Run out at the signal, Go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチして手と手叩いて 重ねるそのメモリーは 明日へのエネルギー
High-five, clap hand in hand, piling up memories as energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよもっと先へ 君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
Now let's go further ahead, with you, a happy lucky life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いつく その日まで 涙なんて振り切るくらい
Until the day I catch up to the dream I saw that day, shaking off tears—
もっとスピードアップ どんな未来になっても 後悔しないよ
Speed up more! No matter what future comes, I won't regret it.
自分自身選んだ道 踏み出せ迷わずに
The path I chose myself, step forward without hesitation!
落ち込んで 進めなくなったときは Wake up!
When you get down and can't move forward, wake up!
思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Think back on the memories of when we dreamed.
手と手で奏でる 響きあうめくるめく夢を君とだけ
Playing hand in hand, a dizzying dream with only you!
ハイタッチその都度に 繋がっていく心 一人じゃないことを 気づかせてくれたよね
Every time we high-five, hearts connect, reminding me I'm not alone!
ハイタッチして手と手叩いて 奏でるそのメロディーが世界に届くまで
High-five, clap hand in hand, until our melody reaches the world!
この夢は続いてく 君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
This dream continues, with you, a happy lucky life!
めぐりめぐる日々を
With no time to even catch my breath,
たどり夢見たすてーじへ
I've been running through.
孤独その日を見つめて
Lonely days are over now!
お母さんは君とだけ
Mother, you're the only one...
手と手を鳴らすたび
Every time we clap our hands,
小さなビッグバン
There's a tiny big bang!
無限のそのチカラを受けて進め!
Receive that infinite power and march on!
ハイタッチ!
High-touch!
手叩いて
Clap your hands,
奏でるメロディーを
and play the melody!
合図に走り出せGo!
Run out on cue, Go!
君となら怖くない
With you, I'm not afraid of anything!
ハイタッチ手叩いて
High-touch, clap your hands,
重ねるそのメモリーは
and let those memories pile up!
明日へのエネルギーyeah!
Energy for tomorrow, yeah!
さあ行こうもっと先へ
Let's go further ahead!
君とならHappy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a happy lucky life!
というわけで皆さん!
Everyone!
お空スバル7周年記念ライブ
Thank you so much for joining
らーぶみににおこしくださり
the Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live,
ありがとうございます!
"Love Me"!
いぇーい!
Yay!
ちわーっ!このライブに来ておじぎすばー!
Thank you so much for coming to this live!
よろしくお願いしまーす!
Please show us lots of love!
というわけでついにらーぶみがはじまるはじまるー!
And so, "Love Me" is finally starting!
今日のですね配信のハッシュタグは右上のこちらになりますので
Today's stream hashtag is right up here,
ぜひよろしくお願いしまいっぱいにえーお空スバル7周年ライブおつをつけてたくさんつぶやいてください!
so please use it to tweet a lot while enjoying
すばるもチェックしたいと思います!
the Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live!
そして皆さん気付きましたか?
And everyone, did you notice?
なんと今までも可愛かったんですけどでもより可愛くしていただきましたニューすばるです!
We've got a brand new Subaru costume!
よろしくお願いしまーす!
Please show us some love!
どうですか?かわいい?かわいい!
Isn't it cute? So cute!
ぜひですねたくさんスクショ撮ってねえついいよしてください!
Be sure to take lots of screenshots
ぽすとねぽすとしてください!
and post them!
そしてですねすばるはねにね通常のねすばるもね見てほしいのでちょっと着替えてきていいですか?
And hey, I want you to see my regular Subaru outfit too,
着替えてきます!じゃ行ってきまーす!
so let me go change real quick!
うわー!わあ!通常衣装のニュースバー!
Tada! My regular news anchor outfit,
そしてなんと帽子がねついに着れるようになった!やった!
and get this—I can finally wear a cap!
ついに着れるようになりました!
I can finally wear hats now!
どうですか?かわいいすか?とてもねえより可愛く作っていただきました髪の毛もねさらさらー
How is it? It's so cute!
もう本当にねありがとうございます!
Thank you all so much!
そして可愛いといえばなんこちらのおステージ!
And speaking of "cute," look at this stage!
とてもね可愛いです!すばるあのすごくゲームが好きなのでこのピクセルっぽい感じでね今年はね作っていただきました!
It's super cute! Subaru loves games so much,
イェーイ!すばるのダックもいる!
so they made this pixel-art style stage for us! Yay!
そしてなんとでもこのピクセルスバルたちももうめっちゃかわいいです!
There's even pixel Subaru ducks! They are so, so cute!
これが一番見せたかったと言ってるもう過言ではない!
To say this is the cutest thing I've ever shown you isn't even an exaggeration!
ということでですねこんな素敵なステージでさせていただいてとてもしあわあ!
So, I got to perform on this amazing stage,
なんとシレっと着替えれました!
and I managed to change my clothes in a flash!
こんにちは!やっぱねアイドル衣装ねでねやっていきたいと思いますのでぜひ
Hello! You know, I've always wanted to shine as bright as possible
アイドル衣装すばるもですねいっぱいスクショ撮ってね
for everyone wearing my idol outfit,
ポストしてください!よろしくお願いしまーす!
so I'm so happy all my dreams came true. Thank you so much!
はいということでここまではなんとふれあですウォッチミーハイタッチメモリーのね3曲をお届けしたんですけど
So far, we've performed three songs from "Watch Me" and "High-Touch Memory."
もうすべてですねすばるにとって思い出深い楽曲で特にふれあですは
These are all such memorable songs for me, especially "Watch Me."
ぜんぜんこのおニュースバルになったらもう1番にねみんなにね披露したいなと思っていたので夢叶いしもなのですめちゃ嬉しいありがとうございます!
I always dreamed of shining the absolute brightest for everyone once I became Oozora Subaru.
はいということでもうねここからはですねなんと何が起こるか分からない!
Now, who knows what's going to happen next?
ゲストが出てくるかもしれないし出てこないかもしれないし
We might have a guest show up, or maybe not!
もう何が起こるか分からないということでえーそんなねライブをお楽しみにこのあともおもうどんどんね盛り上がって楽しんでいくぞ!始まる始まるー!
You never know what's coming next, so let's keep having fun and rocking out!
「あたしの全力受け止めて♡」
"Catch all of my overflowing love!"
きゅっ きゅん ら たっちゅら めに めに
Catchy, catchy, love, touch, love, me, me!
きゅっ きゅん ら たっちゅら しゅきしゅきしゅしゅ
Catchy, catchy, love, touch, love, shuki-shuki-shushu!
始まりをサルベース 想い出のスクロール
Starting on the monkey base, scrolling through memories
長いようで一瞬 それなりには成長しました
It seemed long, yet in an instant, we've grown
嬉しくて泣いた日 悲しくて笑った日も
Days we cried with joy, and days we smiled with sorrow,
ひとつひとつが 君と僕を繋いだ奇跡だから 忘れないよ
every single one is a miracle connecting you and me, so I won't forget.
願えば何処へでも行けるさ 鮮やかな日々を駆け抜ける
If you wish, you can go anywhere, running through vibrant days.
心はカメラじゃ映せない だから今ちゃんと見ていて 僕のことを
The heart cannot be captured on camera, so look closely at me right now.
ねぇ、最高のサクセスストーリーを その瞳に焼き付けたいの
Hey, I want to burn the ultimate success story into those eyes.
輝け ULTRA FLASH!!!
Shine, ULTRA FLASH!!!
始まりのメロディ 色褪せないフィルム
The melody of the beginning, a film that never fades,
記憶を彩る 大切な軌跡
cherished milestones coloring our memories.
そう、歌えばそこに君がいたから
Yes, because you were there whenever I sang,
どんなに挫けそうでも 信じてきたんだ
no matter how close I was to breaking, I kept believing.
Love is MY RAIL
瞬きのシャッター切ったら 君への想いが加速する
The moment I snap the shutter, my feelings for you accelerate.
溢れそうな愛を届けたいから だから今声の限り 歌にするMy Days
I want to deliver this overflowing love, so now I'll turn it into song, My Days.
UndoもRedoも付いていないThis game 最高出力でDrive me, DAYS of DASH
This game has no Undo or Redo, drive me at max output, DAYS of DASH!
今やっとRealize 願いはBeat your Heart 一緒に見たい、夢の続き
Now I finally Realize, my wish is Beat your Heart, I want to see the continuation of the dream together,
ここからまた続いていく
continuing on from here.
こんなに大きくなりました
We've grown so big now,
だからmany-manyな約束どどっとプリーズ♡
so please give us lots and lots of promises!
もりもりmany-manyに返すから！
We'll pay you back in abundance!
しゅーきゅーしゅーきゅーしゅーきゅーぷりーむなおネガイきいて！
Hear our super-cute, supreme wish!
わたしあいた〜い♡
I want to see you!
day by day
超many-manyキュウギュッとエールをぷり〜ず♡
Please give us your super many tight cheers!
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
We'll definitely return it twofold!
手渡しじゃ何年かかるかな
I wonder how many years it'd take to hand-deliver,
へびーすぎじゃない！？でもいいんじゃない！？
isn't that too heavy?! But isn't that fine?!
Gimme!! いつも愛をアリ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you always for your love.
甘いだけじゃダメだけどね
Just being sweet isn't enough,
今日くらいは許してよ…hum
but please forgive me just for today... hum.
大事な話だからもうちょ～～～～っと
It's an important talk, so just a little mooooore—
気合いだけで言えるこの精神誠意をきいてくれますか？
will you listen to this sincere heart spoken with pure spirit?
だから超many-manyな約束どどっとプリーズ♡
So please give us lots and lots of promises!
もりもりmany-manyに返すから！
We'll pay you back in abundance!
しゅーきゅーしゅーきゅーしゅーきゅーぷりーむなおネガイきいて！
Hear our super-cute, supreme wish!
わたしあいた〜い♡
I want to see you!
day by day
超many-manyキュウギュッとエールをぷり〜ず♡
Please give us your super many tight cheers!
絶対ゼッタイ倍で返すから！
We'll definitely return it twofold!
手渡しじゃ何年かかっても
No matter how many years hand-delivery takes,
伝えたいじゃない！届けたいじゃない！
I want to convey it! I want to reach you!
Gimme!! いつも愛をアリ・ガ・ト・ウ
Gimme!! Thank you always for your love.
きゅっきゅん きゅっきゅん らだっちゅらめにめに oh yeah
Kyun-kyun, kyun-kyun, radacchu ra me-ni-me-ni oh yeah!
キュンキュンキュンポクンとー？
Kyun-kyun-kyun pokunto?
すっ…とよろしくね♡
Please treat us well... ♡
ゆらゆらり はらはらり 色とりどり 乱れ咲き 花の街 思い出すこの空から
Swaying gently, soft and fleeting, vibrant colors bloom wildly in flower town, from this sky I remember.
百花繚乱 作詞・作曲 幾田りら
[Title: Hyakka Ryoran / Lyrics & Music: Lilas Ikuta]
ひょんな出来事から やってきたこの場所は 遥か遠くにあった 煌びやかな舞台
The place I arrived at from an unexpected event was a dazzling stage far away.
はっとするほど 鮮やかな世界があるんだと知った
I learned that such a breathtakingly vibrant world exists.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていくその度に あっと言わせような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
Each time I answer your formidable challenges, with astounding, bizarrely imaginative matching answers,
辿り着いたその先に 新しい景色が待っているんだ
a new scenery awaits at the destination I've reached.
摩訶不思議なミステリー 次から次に起こるたび
Whenever an uncanny mystery happens one after another,
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみましょう
let's expose even the clever tricks.
どんな難題でも 種や仕掛けはあるんだ
No matter the difficulty, there are always methods and traps.
副作用は気にしない 必ず導き出すから
I won't worry about side effects, I'll definitely guide us through.
あ この場所で触れた 人の哀しみや喜びが
Ah, the human sorrow and joy I've touched in this place,
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
every single one of them makes my heart tremble.
はっとしちゃうほど 鮮やかな世界がここにあるんだ
A breathtakingly vibrant world exists right here.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていく毎日に
In my everyday life of answering your formidable challenges,
あっと言わせような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
with astounding, bizarrely imaginative matching answers,
辿り着いたその先に 新しい私が見待っているんだ
a new me is waiting at the destination I've reached.
あの頃は想像もしていない 未来が咲き始めてる
A future I couldn't have imagined back then is starting to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
I guess days like this aren't so bad either.
ゆらゆらり ひらりらり 離れては 寄り添って
Swaying gently, dancing lightly, drifting apart and drawing close,
そよぎ風に身を任せ 幽夜に舞う
leaving myself to the gentle breeze, dancing in the moonlit night.
ああ この場所で触れた 人の哀しみや喜びがある
Ah, the human sorrow and joy I've touched in this place exist,
そのひとつひとつが 心を震わせる
and every single one of them makes my heart tremble.
ああ といわせような 奇想天外な答え合わせで
Ah, with astounding, bizarrely imaginative matching answers...
辿り着いたその先に 新しい私が待っているんだ
Waiting for me at the end of the journey I've reached is a brand new me.
あの頃は想像もしてない
A future I couldn't even imagine back then
未来が咲き始めてる こんな日々も悪くはないかな
is beginning to bloom. Days like this aren't so bad, are they?
戦った 戦った 戦った 戦った
I fought, I fought, I fought, I fought.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり 離れては寄り添って
Drifting and fluttering, parting and drawing close,
騒ぐ風に身を任せ 自由に舞う
surrendering to the stirring wind, dancing freely.
KONNANじゃないっ！
This isn't right!
あの夢も 憧れも
Those dreams and yearnings,
落書きのままボヤけて 消える寸前
blurry like graffiti, right before fading away.
「コレガイイ?」 「コレデイイ?」
"Is this good?" "Is this fine?"
ふてくされている鏡に
in the sulking mirror,
何度も問いかけた
I asked over and over again.
泣きたい日も くじけそうな日も 乗り越えよう
On days I want to cry, or feel like giving up, I'll overcome them.
光を浴びなきゃ
I have to bathe in the light!
夢というツボミは 開かないから
Because the bud called a dream won't open otherwise.
Are you ready GO!
走り出そう 取り急ぎ さあ スタート！
Let's start running, hurry up and start!
うつむかないっ！ すりむかないっ！
Don't look down! Don't scrape yourself!
明日は絶対もっとShiny!
Tomorrow will definitely be even shinier!
ジブン次第っ！ つかめ未来っ！
It's up to you! Grasp the future!
今すぐスタートボタン 押してみよう
Let's press the start button right now!
私はこんなんじゃないはず！
I shouldn't be like this!
スイッチオン One more GO!
Switch on One more GO!
諦めも 言い訳も
Resignation and excuses,
取りまとめ リスタート！
bundle them up and restart!
「たられば」に すがるには まだまだ若すぎじゃない？
Aren't we still too young to cling to 'what ifs'?
七転び 八起きでGO!
Fall seven times, stand up eight, let's go!
何度もリセットボタン
Hitting the reset button over and over,
どんな夢も 信じてみよう
let's believe in every single dream.
こんなんじゃないはず
I shouldn't be like this!
信じてみよう 私は
Let's believe, I am...
こんなんじゃないはず！
I shouldn't be like this!
スイッチオン One more GO!
Switch on One more GO!
輝いて 輝いて 輝いて 私はこんなんじゃない！
Shining, shining, shining, I shouldn't be like this!
Great Days
Shining justice 芽生えて
Shining justice, burning in me
Brand new bed town 交差する息吹
Brand-new bed town is the place I wanna be
岬から潮風 トンネル抜け鉄塔へ
Salty wind from the cape, through the tunnel to the pylon
引かれ合い小道に迷い込む
drawn together, getting lost in a narrow path
ココロに溶け込む影照らす黄金の“Spirits” それは守り抜く光
Golden 'Spirits' illuminating shadows melting into the heart, that's the light to protect.
Let the voice of love take you higher 集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
Let the voice of love take you higher, transcending even time with gathering power.
1999年 Bizarre Summer
1999 Bizarre Summer
巡る勇気で生きる町 Great Days
Great Days, a town living with circulating courage.
泣けないじゃないピザサマー 巡りゆきて
Can't we cry? Pizza Summer, wandering on...
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me more!
Brand-new days すれ違う景色
Brand-new days, passing scenery,
雲の隙間にさす 光がほら降りそそぎ
Light piercing through cloud gaps shines down.
いにしえの小道へ足を踏み入れ
Stepping onto an ancient path,
きらめき導く街
A city guided by sparkle.
描ける黄金のスピリットそれは果てしない絆
The golden spirit we draw is an endless bond.
Brand-new days Love give you answer
Brand-new days, give you answer,
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
Even at the time of parting, with an unbreakable will,
泣き出さないで ビジネスサマー
Do not cry, business summer!
自分乗り越え 掴み取れ 未来
Overcome yourself and seize the future!
Brand-new voice and plan Take you higher
集まる力で 時さえ越えて
With gathered power, transcending even time,
Brand-new days Love give you answer
Brand-new days, give you answer,
別れの時さえ 砕けぬ意志で
Even at the time of parting, with an unbreakable will,
泣き出さないで ビジネスサマー
Do not cry, business summer!
交わす勇気 醸す賛歌
A hymn brewed from exchanged courage,
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me more!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me more!
というわけで、グレートデイズをお届けいたしました！
And so, we brought you "Great Days"!
みんな楽しんでくれましたかー？
Did everyone enjoy it?
いや、ここまではですね、まず、ウマ娘ラシューシュ...
Well, up to this point, first, "Uma Musume"...
この曲はですね、すばるもめちゃくちゃね
As for this song, Subaru was also extremely...
もうこの曲はもともと大好きで絶対にやろうって決めてたんですけど
I originally loved this song so much and decided I definitely wanted to do it,
その結果ね、見事ね、あの、ウマ娘のね
and as a result, splendidly, um, with Umamusume's...
アプリめちゃやり込みました、ありがとうございました！
I played the app a lot, thank you very much!
でもすごくね、あの踊って楽しかったです！
But it was really, um, so much fun to dance to!
そしてですね、こんなんじゃない、もうこの曲はですね
And then, not just this, this song is...
夢かなわしものになった時点で絶対にやろうって思ってたんですけど、え、ノエルちゃんとすうにね
I had decided to do it for sure once it became a reality, and, um, with Noel-chan and Suu...
もう絶対にペンライトを振ってほしいと思って、もうやませていただきました！
I wanted them to wave penlights for sure, so I asked them to join!
どうだったかな、みんな楽しんでもらえたらとっても嬉しいです！
I hope everyone enjoyed it, I'd be so happy!
そして「グレートデイズ」はですね、もうすばの大好きなジョジョ4部の曲なんですけど
And "Great Days" is one of Subaru's absolute favorite songs from Jojo Part 4,
もう絶対にね、もうこれでバトンをつなぐんだと、こうやってぐるぐるぐるぐる回してね
and I wanted to pass on the baton with this, spinning around like this,
今年もね、飛ばさせていただいたんですけど
and let it fly again this year too,
みんなスバルの魂と書いてプライドと読む、この魂のバトンを見ていただけましたか？
did you all get to see this baton of soul, spelled "Subaru's soul" and read as "pride"?
グッズは4種類あります！めちゃめちゃあるということで、早速見ていきましょう！
There are 4 types of merch! Since there are so many, let's take a look right away!
イラストはしぐれうい先生に書いていただきました！がーちゃんいつもありがとう！
The illustrations were drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei! Thank you as always, Gaa-chan!
イラストテーマは「オードアイドルすばる」です！
The illustration theme is "Audrey Idol Subaru"!
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう、まずは、こちら！
Now let's look at the details, first is this!
スバルがファンサ！ラバーマット！こちらの商品はですね、オードアイドルのスバルが…
"Subaru is Fan Service! Rubber Mat!" This item features Subaru as an Audrey Idol...
新しいラバーマットになります！
It's a new rubber mat!
以前ラバーマットを出したのはえーと4年前なので、
The last time I released a rubber mat was, um, four years ago,
当時買えなかった人もね、前のおを使っててもボロボロになっちゃったよっていう人も、ぜひ新しくチェックしてみてくださーい！
so if you couldn't buy one back then, or if your old one is worn out, please check this out!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
スバルがファンサ！カードスリーブ！
Subaru's Fan Service! Card Sleeves!
こちらはですね、ラバーマットに合わせてカードスリーブも出してみました！
These have been released to match the rubber mat!
ラバーマットと合わせて使えば、スバルに応援されているような気持ちになれるかも？ということでぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
Used together, you might feel cheered on by Subaru, so definitely check these out too!
そして続いてこちら！
And continuing with this!
マスコット大集合カードケース！いえーい！
Mascot All-Star Card Case! Yay!
カードスリーブときたらね、やっぱケースも必要でしょうということで、
Since we have card sleeves, of course we need a case too,
もうスバルの、スバルのダックから、なんとワタアメウサギまで、そしてスバトモマートというようなね、たくさんみんなが集まった、カードケースを作ってみました！
so we made a card case featuring everyone gathered together—from Subaru Duck to Watame Usagi and Subaru-tomo Mart!
側面のですね、カードを見せつけられる窓がついているので、今回のカードスリーブをバシッと挿して見せるもよし、
On the side is a window to display cards, so you can insert the sleeve to show it off,
そのね、切り札を見せつけるもよしということで、ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください！
or show off your trump card—be sure to check this out as well!
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー 動物パジャマ衣装ver.！
Plush Keychain Animal Pajamas Ver.!
こちらはですね、なんかスバル自身のぬいぐるみってあんまり出してないか、もうみたいなことを思ったので、ちょっとねアイドル衣装とついに成るイメージのおふっぽい動物パジャマ衣装で作ってみました！
Since I haven't released many plushies of myself, I made one in a cozy animal pajama style that pairs with the idol outfit!
ぜひね、この可愛らしいスバルもいろんなところに連れ回してみてくださーい！
Please take this adorable Subaru around with you everywhere!
そしてなんと、フルセット購入特典もあります！
And what's more, there's a full-set purchase bonus!
それではこちら、どん！
So here it is, ta-da!
ステッカーがなんとね今回付いております！とても可愛いです！
A sticker is included this time! It's super cute!
スバルずっと前からステッカー出してみたかったなってずっと持ってだったので、今回ですね、夢が叶って嬉しいです！
I've always wanted to release a sticker, so I'm so happy my dream came true!
ぜひみんなのね、お気に入りの場所にペタッと貼ってみてください！
Please stick it on your favorite spot!
そしてでは改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！どん！
And now, here is the full set again! Ta-da!
やっぱりね、買うならね、シールも付いてお得なフルセットのがいいか、も！ということでぜひねチェックしてみてください！
If you're buying, getting the full set with stickers is a great deal, so be sure to check it out!
以上！大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ紹介でしたー！
That's all for the Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live merch introduction!
どれもですね、素敵なグッズに仕上がっておりますので、ぜひですね、要チェックだー！
Every item has turned out wonderful, so definitely be sure to check them out!
絶対に、絶対にチェックしてくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
Make sure to check them out! Thank you!
はい、そしてですね、なんとこの衣装でのニュースバル、ちょっとね可愛いのでとても、ぜひスクショ撮っていただきたいです！
And this new Subaru in this outfit is super cute, so I'd love for you to take screenshots!
わあ、あ、そっか後ろ向いたら撮れないや。
Ah, right, if I turn around I can't take pictures.
どうぞー！可愛いですか？
Go ahead! Is it cute?
スバルのこのね、衣装のね、好きポイントはですね、この後ろのとっても可愛い、ととっても可愛いリボンがですね、
My favorite point of this outfit is this very cute, very cute ribbon on the back...
可愛いー！どうですか？え、マジで語彙力ないな今日。
Cute! How is it? Man, my vocabulary is terrible today.
でも本当にね、可愛いっていうのいでね、ぜひみんないっぱいねポストしてください！よろしくお願いします！
It's super cute, so everyone please post lots of pictures! Thank you!
そしてですね、こんなに楽しいライブも、もうなんと終盤！わあ！
And now, this fun live is already reaching its final stretch! Wow!
それではここからはですね、もうラストに向けてですね、バーっと駆け抜けていきたいと思いますので、ぜひねみんなもね、最後まで楽しんでいただけるとすごく嬉しいです！
From here on, we're going to dash towards the finish line, so I'd be super happy if you all enjoy it until the end!
はい、ということで、それではもうラストだよ！始めちゃうってわけ、始めちゃうよ！
Alright, so it's already the finale! We're starting it, we're starting it!
よし、始めたいと思います。
Alright, I'd like to start.
はい、それでは聞いてください、「ray」。
Yes, then please listen to "ray".
お別れしたのはもっと前の事だったような
It seems like it was a long time ago that we said goodbye,
悲しい光は封じ込んで 踵擦り減らしなんだ
keeping the sad light inside, wearing down my heels.
君と言いた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
When I was with you I could see it, now I can no longer see it.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探してる
Vaguely looking for a transparent comet, but that's all I'm searching for.
しょっちゅう歌を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I often sang songs, melodies just for that moment.
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all...
しょうちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I always sang songs, with melodies just for those moments.
いつまでどこまでなんて
Asking how long or how far,
正常か異常かなんて
Or whether it's normal or abnormal—
考える暇もない程 歩くのは大変だ
I don't even have time to think, walking is so tough.
楽しい方がずっといいよ ごまかして笑っていくよ
Having fun is always better, so I'll just fake a smile and go on.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, that pain won't disappear just because you forget it.
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality rewrites the path we built with our ideals.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
Memories remain as a brilliance upon those tracks.
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we say goodbye? What was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を 前に長く伸ばしている
A sad light stretches my shadow far ahead of me.
時々熱が出るよ 時間がある時眠るよ
Sometimes I get a fever, and sleep when I have time.
夢だと解かるその中で 君と会ってからまた行こう
Knowing it's a dream, I'll meet you there before going on.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from clear skies,
終わらない暗闇にも
Even in the endless darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら すぐ銀河の中だ
If you picture the stars, you're instantly in the galaxy.
あんまり泣かなくなっても 靴を新しくしても
Even if I don't cry as much, even if I get new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, that pain won't disappear just because you forget it.
伝えたかったことが きっとあったんだろうな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you.
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It's probably cliché, but even so...
お別れしたことは 出会ったことと繋がっている
Saying goodbye is connected to the fact that we met.
あの透明な彗星は 透明だから無くならない
That transparent comet won't disappear because it's transparent.
丸バツ三角どれかなんて 皆と比べてどうかなんて
Whether it's a circle, cross, or triangle, how it compares to everyone else—
確かめる間も無い程 生きるのは最高だ
I don't even have time to check, living is amazing!
あんまり泣かなくなっても ごまかして笑っていくよ
Even if I don't cry as much, I'll just fake a smile and go on.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, that pain won't disappear just because you forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の 始まりには 君がいる
It's alright, you are at the beginning of this light.
いっせーのせで 踏み込むゴールライン 僕らは
Stepping over the goal line all at once, we...
何も 何も まだ知らぬ
Still know nothing at all.
一線越えて 振り返るともうない 僕らは
Crossing the line, looking back, it's already gone, we...
何も 何も まだ知らぬ
Still know nothing at all.
うだって うだって うだってく
Staggering, staggering, staggering onward,
煌めく汗が こぼれるのさ
Glistening sweat spills over.
覚えてないことも たくさんあっただろう
There must have been so many things we don't remember.
誰も 彼も シルエット
Everyone, anyone, a silhouette
大事にしてたもの
What I held so dear
忘れたふりをしたんだよ
I pretended to forget
なにもないよ 笑えるさ
There's nothing left, I can laugh it off
いっせーのせで 思い出す少年僕らは
On the count of three, we, once boys,
なにもかもを 欲しがった
Wanted everything in the world
わかってるって あぁ気づいてるって
I know, ah, I've realized,
時計の針は 日々は 止まらない
The hands of the clock, the days, never stop
奪って 奪って 奪っていく 流れる時と記憶
Stealing away, flowing time and memories
遠く遠くなって 覚えてないことも たくさんあっただろう
Growing so far away, there must be so much we don't remember
誰も 彼も シルエット
Everyone, anyone, a silhouette
恐れてやまぬこと 知らないふりをしたんだよ
I pretended not to know what I feared endlessly
なにもないよ 笑えるさ
There's nothing left, I can laugh it off
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる
Fluttering, fluttering, dancing down
この葉のように 揺れ動くこと なく
Like these leaves, without swaying uncertainly,
焦燥感過たしてたいよ
Yearning to live past the impatience
覚えてないことも たくさんあったけど
Though there was so much we don't remember,
きっと ずっと 変わらないものがあることを 教えてくれたあなたは
You, who taught me that surely, forever, some things never change,
消えぬ 消えぬ 消えぬ
Will never, ever, ever fade away—
シルエット 大事にしたもの
Silhouette, what I held so dear,
もって大人になるんだ
Growing up holding onto it
どんな時も 離さずに 守り続けよう
No matter what, let's keep protecting it without letting go
そしたら いつのかにかなにもかもを
Then, someday, everything—
笑えるさ
We can laugh it off
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる この葉が 飛んでゆく
Fluttering, fluttering, dancing down, these leaves are flying away
描いた未知の キャンバス 重ねる景色
The canvas of painted unknown, overlapping scenery
繋いでみて 繰り返していく衝動
Try connecting them, a repeating impulse
揺らいだ 目の前に広がる世界
The wavering world spreading out before my eyes
星屑のメロディ 歌に乗せた
A stardust melody put into song
クラッと鮮やかに 眩ませるように
Dizzily, vividly, as if dazzling me
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
I'll run through it, starlight!
そう僕らは いつしか夢の中 惹かれて
Yes, we were drawn into a dream before we knew it
ただがむしゃらに 走り続けたよ
And just kept running recklessly onward
無限の宇宙に響いた キミを照らす声は
The voice echoing into the infinite cosmos, illuminating you,
どこへだって きらり 飛んでゆけるんだ
Can fly away sparkling anywhere at all!
愉快な仲間と 歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days walked with cheerful friends
掴んでみて 指先の一等星
Try grasping it, the first-magnitude star at your fingertips
滲んでゆく 目の前に広がった限界は
The limits spreading out before my eyes, blurring away—
皆の手重ねて ぶっ壊して
Let's stack our hands together and smash them down!
吸い込まれそうな 夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that looks like it will swallow us,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
Now I shout out, starlight!
そう僕らは いつでもそばで笑い合って
Yes, we always laughed together by each other's side
あふれる声が 遠くこだまする 願いのかけらを
The overflowing voices echo far away, holding the pieces of our wishes...
願いのかけらを灯した
I lit the fragments of our wishes,
キミの腕を引いて
pulling you by the arm.
どこへだって
Wherever we go,
きらり 飛んでゆけるんだ
we can fly away sparkling bright!
ちょっと不安な日も
Even on days when I feel a bit uneasy,
魔法をかけてハッピー
cast a spell and be happy!
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with superhuman strength!
アクアブルーに染まる
Dyed in aqua blue,
大空へ仕掛けた
launched into the vast sky,
鼓動が弾んでく
our heartbeats are bounding.
そう僕らは この日をずっと待ってたんだ
Yes, we've been waiting for this day all along.
まだ覚めないで Stellar
Don't wake up yet, Stellar!
僕らは 止まらない
We won't stop,
その光が消える 1秒前まで走り続けるよ
running on until just one second before the light fades.
無限の宇宙に響いた キミを照らす声を
The voice echoing in the infinite cosmos, illuminating you—
強く抱いて きらり
hold it tight and sparkle,
輝いてゆけ
shining ever on!
いつだって愛情が先に走り出す 僕らのランウェイを
Always with affection running ahead on our runway,
頑丈とラッキーを盾に進みます あゆレディ？
armed with sturdiness and luck, we march forward. Are you ready?
転んだって泣いたって僕ら 慣れてるよ 受け身はパーフェクト
Even if we fall or cry, we're used to it—our fall recovery is perfect!
笑ってくれてありがと！ また僕は歌えるよ
Thanks for smiling with me! I can sing again.
人生は不安ばっか 正直自信はないけど
Life is full of anxieties, and honestly I lack confidence,
君の隣だけは 譲る気はないのです！
but I have no intention of giving up being right by your side!
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ 君の目にどう映るかな
How does this miraculous world where we met reflect in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る 僕だけの太陽だといいな
I hope it looks like my very own sun, clearer than the blue sky.
不確かな永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to sing about the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続くあいまいみーゆえにラブミー
In this corner of the planet, amidst our ambiguous "me", Love Me!
ナンセンスな現実が 心を乱していた
Nonsense reality used to disturb my heart,
ラッキーの天秤の裏側にあるアンラッキー
but on the flip side of luck's scale lies unluck.
転んだって泣いたって僕ら 立ち上がる 七転八倒さ
Even if we fall and cry, we get back up—that's falling seven times and rising eight!
笑ってくれてありがと！ まだ僕は走れるよ
Thanks for smiling! I can still keep running.
人生の期待感は 正直膨らむばっかでさ
Expectations in life honestly just keep swelling up,
君の心の中 灯る日だまりなのだ！
so they're a warming hearth glowing inside your heart!
僕らが暮らしてる奇跡の時代 君のことどう照らすかな
How will this miraculous era we live in illuminate you?
星より煌めいた 僕らしい太陽になれたら
If I could become a sun more dazzling and true to myself than the stars,
不確かな永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす今を楽しみたい
rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to enjoy the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続くあいまいみーゆえにラヴミーアイラブユー伝えたいの！
In this corner of the planet, amidst our ambiguous "me", Love Me, I love you, I want to tell you!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much today!
ここまで活動できたのは 応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
The only reason I've been able to keep going this far is thanks to everyone's support!
いつも本当にありがとう！ みんな大好きだぞ！
Thank you always so much! I love you all so much!
ああ健やかな時も ああ病める時もきっと
Ah, both in healthy times and ailing times surely,
伝えたいよこのメロディー
I want to convey this melody to you.
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ 君の目にどう映るかな
How does this miraculous world where we met reflect in your eyes?
青より澄み渡る 僕だけの太陽だといいな
I hope it looks like my very own sun, clearer than the blue sky.
不確かな永遠より 僕は 二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I want to sing about the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続くあいまいみーゆえにラヴミーアイラブユー伝えたいの！
In this corner of the planet, amidst our ambiguous "me", Love Me, I love you, I want to tell you!
これからも、楽しい事いっぱいに一緒にはうね！
Let's keep doing lots of fun things together!